Guide to the Faculty Senate records ARCH020
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
Faculty Senate records
1960-2014
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
University of Hartford. Faculty Senate
ARCH020
9.33 Linear Feet (21 containers)
The collection consists of faculty senate meeting minutes, committee records, and subject files from 1960 to 2014.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to all researchers. However, due to the intermittent presence of confidential and/or sensitive materials which are restricted under the University Archives restriction protocols, all requested materials must be reviewed by the Archivist prior to granting access to the records.
Historical Note
The faculty senate is the official organization of the faculty of the University of Hartford. The senate includes representation of all of the schools of the University. Representatives are elected for three year terms.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of faculty senate meeting minutes, committee records, and subject files from 1960 to 2014. The collection documents the academic issues and decisions made by the Faculty Senate primarily concerning faculty policies and curriculum of the University.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in three series: 1. Minutes and other meeting records, II. Committees, III. Subject Files.
minutes (administrative records); Correspondence; University of Hartford -- Curricula; University of Hartford; University of Hartford. Faculty Senate
- Minutes and other meeting records, 1960 Nov - 2014 Apr; I
  - 1960 Nov - 1968 Dec (Box Minutes 1)
  - 1969 Jan - 1973 May (Box Minutes 2)
  - 1973 Sep - 1978 Nov (Box Minutes 3)
  - 1978 Nov - 1982 May (Box Minutes 4)
  - 1982 Sep - 1984 May (Box Minutes 5)
  - 1984 Sep - 1989 Aug (Box Minutes 6)
  - 1989 Sep - 2005 Apr (Box Minutes 7)
  - 2005 May - 2008 Sep (Box Minutes 8)
  - 2008 Oct - 2012 Oct (Box Minutes 9)
  - 2012- Nov - 2014 Apr (Box Minutes 10)
- Committees, 1973-2014; II
  - Academic Standards and Procedures Committee, 1981 Jan; 1982 Jan (Box Committees 1, Folder 1)
  - Bookstore Committee, 1980-1981 (Box Committees 1, Folder 2)
  - Budget Committee, 1981 Aug (Box Committees 1, Folder 3)
  - Calendar Committee, 1981-1982 (Box Committees 1, Folder 4)
  - Coffin Grant Committee, 1980-1982 (Box Committees 1, Folder 5)
  - Commencement Committee, 1981 (Box Committees 1, Folder 6)
  - Committee Meetings, 2005 (Box Committees 1, Folder 7)
  - Committee Members, 1981-1982; 2004-2009 (Box Committees 1, Folder 8-11)
  - Committee on Degrees and Ceremonials, 1986-1987 (Box Committees 1, Folder 12-13)
  - Committee Year End Reports, 1980-1981 (Box Committees 1, Folder 14)
  - Computer and Technology Committee, 2004 Sep (Box Committees 1, Folder 15)
  - Consortium Committee, 1980-1981 (Box Committees 1, Folder 16)
  - Constitution and Bylaws Committee, 1977-2009 (Box Committees 1, Folder 17-20)
  - Convocation Planning Committee, 1988-1991 (Box Committees 1, Folder 21)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1980; 2004-2014 (Box Committees 1, Folder 22, Box Committees 2, Folder 1-15, Box Committees 3, Folder 1)
  - Dean Senate Joint Committee, 1980-1981; 2004 (Box Committees 3, Folder 2)
  - Education Committee, 2006 (Box Committees 3, Folder 3)
  - Executive Committee, 1976 Jun - 1991-Nov; 2005 Apr - 2008 Oct (Box Committees 3, Folder 4-15, Box Committees 4, Folder 1-7)
  - Governance Committee, 1973 (Box Committees 4, Folder 8)
  - Graduate Studies Committee, 1980-1982 (Box Committees 4, Folder 9)
  - Grievance Committee, 2004 (Box Committees 4, Folder 10)
  - Professional Standards Committee, 1980-1982; 1988 Nov (Box Committees 4, Folder 11-12)
  - Sabbatical Committee, 1980-1982 (Box Committees 4, Folder 13)
  - Strategic Planning Committee, 2004-2005 (Box Committees 4, Folder 14)
  - Student Affairs Committee, 1980-1982; 2004 (Box Committees 4, Folder 15-16)
  - Subcommittee on Academic Administration, 1980-1982 (Box Committees 4, Folder 17)
  - Undergraduate Committee, 1980-1982 (Box Committees 4, Folder 18)
  - University Scholars Committee, 1980-1981 (Box Committees 4, Folder 19)
- Subject Files, 1961-2012; III
  - AAUP, 1986-1992 (Box Subject 1)
  - Academic Policies and Procedures Manual, 1981 (Box Subject 1)
  - Academic Standards and Procedures, 1989-1992 (Box Subject 1)
  - Advisory Group, 1980-1982 (Box Subject 1)
  - Annual Meeting, 2006 (Box Subject 1)
  - Annual Report, 2005-2008 (Box Subject 1)
  - Articles, 1981-1982 (Box Subject 1)
  - Barney School of Business, 2006-2007 (Box Subject 1)
  - Benefits Task Force, 2008 (Box Subject 1)
  - Bent, Larsen, Trachtenberg, and Master Teachers Awards, 1988; 2008-2009 (Box Subject 1)
  - Board of Regents, 1979-2006 (Box Subject 2)
  - Budget Advisory Team (BAT), 2005 (Box Subject 2)
  - Budget Parameters, 2006-2007 (Box Subject 2)
  - Business Continuity Program, 2007 (Box Subject 2)
  - Coffin Gant, 2007-2009 (Box Subject 2)
  - Commencement, 1981-1982; 2006 (Box Subject 2)
  - Consortium Sustainability, 2008 (Box Subject 2)
  - Constitution and Bylaws, 1961-1996 (Box Subject 2, Box Subject 3)
  - Constitution and Bylaw Annual Report, 2007 (Box Subject 3)
  - Cooperative Education Program, 1981 (Box Subject 3)
  - Correspondence - C. Guardo Provost, 1980-1982; 2005-2008 (Box Subject 3)
    Scope and Contents
    The file includes correspondence of/with: C. Guardo Provost, Intercampus, Inter-senate, S.J. Trachtenberg, and others.
  - DAES Division Adult Education Services, 1981-1982 (Box Subject 3)
  - Diversity, 2008 (Box Subject 3)
  - Elections, 1981-1982; 2008-2009 (Box Subject 3)
  - Emeriti and Gordon Clark Ramsey, 1998; 2004-2007; undated (Box Subject 3, Box Shared CD Box 1)
    File contains information about the Emeriti Association, as well as Gordon Clark Ramsey. Included is Ramsey's CD "Edwardian Music for Organ."
  - Enrollment Reports, 1979-1981 (Box Subject 3)
  - Environmental/Sustainability, 2009 (Box Subject 3)
  - Extended Temporary Contract, undated (Box Subject 3)
  - Faculty Affairs, 2008 (Box Subject 3)
  - Faculty Club Feasibility Task Force, 1980-1982 (Box Subject 3)
  - Faculty Policy Manuals, 1980-1982; 2004-2007 (Box Subject 3, Box Subject 4)
  - Faculty Senate Members, 1980-1984 (Box Subject 4)
  - Faculty Senate Officers, 2005-2008 (Box Subject 4)
  - Faculty Senator Elctions, 2005-2008 (Box Subject 4)
  - Faculty Senate Schedule, 2007-2008 (Box Subject 4)
  - Faculty Staff Campaign, 1980-1981 (Box Subject 4)
  - Faculty Welfare Committee (FWC) Liason, 1980-1982 (Box Subject 4)
  - Fall Convocation, 1980-1984 (Box Subject 4)
  - Financial Exigency Task Force, 1981 (Box Subject 4)
  - Fiscal Year, 2005-2006 (Box Subject 4)
  - Fiscal Year Plan, 1977, 1980 (Box Subject 4)
  - Forms - Personnel Action Notification, 1995 (Box Subject 4)
  - Forms - Personal Expense Voucher, 1986 (Box Subject 4)
  - Foundation of Future, 2012 (Box Subject 4)
  - Four Credit Curriculum Task Force, 1981-1982 (Box Subject 4)
  - Grading System Task Force, 1976, 1981-1982 (Box Subject 4)
  - Grants and Summer Stipends, 2003-2005, 2008-2010 (Box Subject 4, Box Shared CD Box 1)
    Includes a 3.5 inch floppy disk labelled "Grants Committee 2004-2005 Academic Year."
  - Greenberg Junior Grant, 2005-2006 (Box Subject 4)
  - Higher Education, 1981 (Box Subject 4)
  - History, 1967-1987, Circa 1987 (Box Subject 4)
  - Indicator Report, 2006-2007 (Box Subject 4)
  - Institutional Advancement, 2005 (Box Subject 4)
  - International Studies, 2004 Sep (Box Subject 4)
  - Lists, 1980-1982 (Box Subject 4)
  - Master Teacher Award Task Force, 1980-1982 (Box Subject 4)
  - Minority Task Force, 2007 (Box Subject 4)
  - Miscellaneous, 1981 (Box Subject 5)
  - Miscellaneous University, 1975, 1981 (Box Subject 5)
  - New Faculty Material, 2004-2005 (Box Subject 5)
  - New Senators, 2007-2008 (Box Subject 5)
  - Part Time Faculty, 2005-2008 (Box Subject 5)
  - Part Time and Adjunct Faculty, 2005-2006 (Box Subject 5)
  - Photographs, 1973 Oct 19 (Box Subject 5)
  - Planning Advisory Group, 1980-1982 (Box Subject 5)
  - Prayer Day, 2007-2009 (Box Subject 5)
  - Professional Standards, 2004-2005 (Box Subject 5)
  - Promotion and Tenure Process, Circa 1994 - circa 1996 (Box Subject 5)
  - Promotion and Tenure, 2007 (Box Subject 5)
  - Proposal for Scholars Program, 2008 (Box Subject 5)
  - Proposed Changes to Section XX, 2009 (Box Subject 5)
  - Provost Calendar, 2008-2009 (Box Subject 5)
  - Purchasing Dept. Policy and Procedures Manual, 1979, 2000 (Box Subject 5)
  - Ralph Albernathy, undated (Box Subject 5)
  - Regent Representation, 2005-2006 (Box Subject 5)
  - Reports - Senators to Schools, 1981-1982 (Box Subject 5)
  - Response to Rules Compliance, 2006-2012 (Box Subject 5)
  - Sabbatical, 2007-2009 (Box Subject 5)
  - Senate Calendar, 2012 (Box Subject 5)
  - Senate Records, 2005 (Box Subject 5)
  - Senators, 2003-2008 (Box Subject 5)
  - Senior Forum, 1980-1982 (Box Subject 5)
  - Softball Game, 2011 (Box Subject 5)
  - Speeches, 1977, 1981-1982 (Box Subject 5)
  - Staff Association, 2007-2008 (Box Subject 5)
  - Student Association, 1981-1982 (Box Subject 5)
  - Supervisor's Manual, 2006 (Box Subject 5)
  - Survey Senators, 2005-2007 (Box Subject 5)
  - Teaching Award Task Force, 1980-1982 (Box Subject 5)
  - Teaching Evaluation Task Force, 1981 (Box Subject 6)
  - Trachtenberg, 1988 (Box Subject 6)
  - University Grants, 2006 (Box Subject 6)
  - University Scholar, 2003-2010 (Box Subject 6)
  - Vincent Coffin Grants, 2011-2012 (Box Subject 6)
  - Year End Reports, 2005-2008 (Box Subject 6)
  - Web Material, 2003-2006 (Box Subject 6)
  - Website, 2005-2007 (Box Subject 6)